Guide to the D.C. Front Runners records, 1981-2003 MS2318
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
D.C. Front Runners records
1981-2003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2318
6.5 Linear Feet 12 document boxes and one flat box
This collection contains photographs, correspondence, announcements, flyers, race results, membership records, and financial records documenting the D.C. Front Runners organization between 1981 and 2003. The D.C. Front Runners in a running, walking, and social club for Washington, D.C.'s LGBT community. It was founded in 1981 and is one of dozens of Front Runners clubs in the United States and abroad. The first Front Runners organization was formed in San Francisco in 1978, as a running club with a name inspired by Patricia Nell Warren's novel The Front Runner. The D.C. Front Runners organizes weekly walks and runs, sponsors local running events, and sends runners to local and national races.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographs, correspondence, announcements, flyers, race results, membership records, and financial records documenting the D.C. Front Runners organization between 1981 and 2003. It also contains newsletters documenting other Front Runners organizations in cities in the United States and abroad.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: Newsletters; Events; Membership; Financial; and Photographs.
Biographical / Historical
The D.C. Front Runners in a running, walking, and social club for Washington, D.C.'s LGBT community. It was founded in 1981 and is one of dozens of Front Runners clubs in the United States and abroad. The first Front Runners organization was formed in San Francisco in 1978, as a running club with a name inspired by Patricia Nell Warren's novel The Front Runner. The D.C. Front Runners organizes weekly walks and runs, sponsors local running events, and sends runners to local and national races.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of D.C. Front Runners, 2013 (2013.022)
Cross-country running; Lesbian and gay experience; International Front Runners; D.C. Front Runners
- Newsletters, 1981-2002; Series 1; 1 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains newsletters and other announcements from Front Runners organizations throughout the United States and the world. Materials date from 1981 to 2002.
  - Alpine Frontrunners Club Calgary, 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arizona Frontrunners, 2002; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Baltimore Frontrunners, 2000-2002; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baylands Frontrunners [Cupertino, CA], 2000-2002; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chicago Frontrunners/Frontwalkers, 1991-2002; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - D.C. Front Runners, 1981-1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - D.C. Front Runners, 1988-1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - D.C. Front Runners, 1992-1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - D.C. Front Runners, 1996-2002; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - D.C. Front Runners, 2006-2008; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Denver FrontRunners, 2002; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Eastbay Frontrunners, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Front Runners Atlanta, 2000-2001; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Frontrunners Boston, 2001; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Front Runners of Fort Lauderdale, 1992-2000; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - FrontRunners Johannesburg, 200-2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Frontrunners of Long Beach, 1990; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Front Runners New York, 1990-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Frontrunners de Paris, 2000-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Frontrunners Philadelphia, 2001-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Frontrunners Sacramento, 2000-2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Front Runners San Diego, 1992-2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Frontrunners Toronto, 2000-2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - International Frontrunners, undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - London Frontrunners, 2001-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Los Angeles Frontrunners, 1990-2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Omaha Front Runners/Walkers, 2000-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Orlando Front Runners and Walkers, 2001-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Palm Springs Front Runners and Walkers, 2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pittsburgh Frontrunners, 2000-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Saint Louis Frontrunners, 2000-2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - San Francisco Frontrunners, 2000-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Seattle Frontrunners, 2000-2001; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Sydney Frontrunners, 1992-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Tampa Bay Frontrunners, 2000-2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Newsletter drafts, 1990-1991; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Events, 1982-2000; Series 2; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains invitations, announcements, flyers, correspondence, race results, and planning materials for various events D.C. Front Runners participated in between 1982 and 2000.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Invitations, Announcements, and Flyers, 1982-1984; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, Announcements, and Flyers, 1985-2011; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Race results, 1990-1992; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gay Pride Run '85, 1985; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Celebration '90, 1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lesbian and Gay Pride Run, 1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pride Day, 1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Spring Weekend, 1990; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pride Parade, 1991; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Spring Weekend, 1991; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Spring Front Runner Fest, 1992; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - International Frontrunner Forum, 1993; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pride Day, 1993; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Holiday Party, 1996; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Spring Weekend, 1997; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Spring Fling, 1999; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Capital Pride Festival, 1999-2000; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Membership, 1981-2003; Series 3; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains membership lists, cards, announcements, and correspondence from 1981 to 2003.
  - Membership, 1981-1984; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Membership [1 of 2], 1985-1999; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Membership [2 of 2], 1985-1999; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Membership, 2003; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Membership correspondence, 1987-1997; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ballots, Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Financial, 1981-2001; Series 4; 1.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains bank records and budgets documenting the finances of the D.C. Front Runners from 1981 to 2001.
  - Financial records, 1981; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Financial records, 1982; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1983; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Financial records and By-Laws, 1984; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Financial records, 1985; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Financial records, 1986; Series 4 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Financial records, 1987; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Financial records, 1988; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1989; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Financial records, 1990; Series 4 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Financial records, 1991; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Financial records, 1992; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1993-1999; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Budget, 2001; Series 4 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Photographs, 1987-2002; Series 5; 3 Linear Feet
  Arranged chronologically by event.
  This series contains photographs of D.C. Front Runners members at races and social gatherings between 1987 and 2002. It also contains two copies of the DVD entitled Fast Forward: D.C. Front Runners 30 Years Running, published in 2011.
  - March on Washington, 1987 October 10; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Gay Pride Festival, 1987 June 13; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Halloween Costume Run, 1988 October 29; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - New York Pride, 1990 June 24; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Vancouver - Gay Games III, 1990 August 4; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 10th Anniversary, 1991 August 10; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Williamsburg, 1992 February 23; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Run for Paul A. Webb (Rock Creek Park-DCFR Grove), 1994 November 5; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Catskill Mountain 100k Relay, 1996 August 11; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Philadelphia Distance Run (Half-Marathon), 1996 September 22; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Philadelphia Distance Run Weekend, 1996 September 20-22; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Quilt Weekend (D.C.), 1996 October 11; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Marine Corp Marathon, 1996 October 27; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Baltimore Run, 1996 November 2; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Jingle Bell 10k, 1996 December 8; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Holiday Party, 1996 December; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Spring Flight - Saturday AM Bagels, 1997 April 26; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Sallie Mae 10k (Spring Fling), 1997 April 27; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Spring Fling - Sunday Brunch, 1997 April 27; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Annual Picnic (at Lisa Henderson and Susan Mathias'), 1997 September 14; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Jingle Bell 10k, 1997 December 14; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Holiday Party, 1997 December 14; Series 5 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Williamsburg Colonial Half-Marathon, 1998 February 22; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Spring Fling (Friday Reception, Saturday Group Run and Bagel, Saturday PM Dance, Sunday Brunch), 1998 April 24-26; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Easter Bonnet Run, 1999 April 3; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Spring Fling (Saturday Women's Brunch and Bagels, Saturday PM Cocktails), 1999 April 23; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Capitol Hill Classic, 1999 May 2; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Annual Picnic and Election (Max Jensen's House), 1999 September 12; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Forming International Front Runners/Philadelphia Distance (Meeting, Saturday Dinner, International Front Runners Officers), 1999 September 17-19; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Holiday Party, 1999 December 12; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Williamsburg Half-Marathon, 2000 February 20; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Cherry Blossom, 2000 April 4; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Easter Bonnet Run, 2000 April 22; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Spring Fling Saturday Cocktails, 2000 April 30; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Spring Fling Dinner Saturday (Mill March Weekend), 2000 April 30; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Water Gun Run - Rock Creek Park, 2000 August 12; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 4th International Front Runners - Bercin, 2000 August 23, 28; Series 5 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Annual Picnic and Elections (Tony and Kevin's House), 2000 September 10; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Philadelphia Distance Weekend (Saturday AM Group, Saturday AM Bagels, Sunday Post Run Brunch), 2000 September 15-17; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Army 10 Miler, 2000 October 15; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Marine Corp Marathon (Cross over at Haines Point), 2000 October 22; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Marine Corp Marathon Party (at Charlie and Lennie's), 2000 October 22; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Holiday Party, 2000 December 10; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Easter Bonnet Run, 2001 April 14; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Annual Picnic and Election (at Caroline's), 2001 September 1; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Pride Day, 1988; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Spring Fling, ca. 1995-2000; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Pride, 2000; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Rescue Team, ca. 1990-2000; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Unlabeled Photographs - Gatherings and Events, 1983-1995; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - DC Pride, ca. 1990-2000; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Nantucket, 1999; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - 10th Annual Run and Williamsburg, 1992; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Williamsburg, 1990-2000; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Park Run, ca. 1990-2000; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Unlabeled Photographs - Gatherings and Race, ca. 1988; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Catskills Areas, ca. 1994; Series 5 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Various Events - Spring Fling, Marine Corp Marathon, Gay Games IV, ca 1985-2000; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Various Events - 10th Annual and Social Gatherings, ca. 1990-2000; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - DC Front Runners Photo Album 1 - Various Gatherings and Races (Photographs and Race Results), 1981-1985; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - DC Front Runners Photo Album 2 - Various Gatherins and Races (Photographs and Race Results), 1981-1984; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - DC Front Runners Photo Album 3 - Various Gatherings and Races, 1985-1987; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 5 (1/2))
  - DC Front Runners Photo Album 3 - Various Gatherings and Races (Photographs and Fliers), 1986-1988; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 6 (2/2))
  - Spring Fling (Saturday AM), 2000; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Spring Fling (Saturday Dinner), 2000; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Various Events - Social Gatherings, ca. 1990-2002; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Running Event, ca. 1997; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Members at a Restaurant, 1997 April 11; Series 5 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Various Events - Races and Gatherings (Sallie Mae, Jingle Bell Run, and other unidentified events), 1990-2000; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Various Events - Races, 1983-2000; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Fort Detrick 10K, 2000 November; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Annual Picnic, ca. 2000; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Sallie Mae 10K, 1997; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Pride and Covered Bridges Run, 1997; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Spring Fling and Sallie Mae 10K, 2000; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Organization Awards being given to Members, 2002 September; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Spring Fling and Pride, ca. 1999; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Spring Fling (Saturday AM Run), 2000 April 29; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Jingle Bell Run, ca. 1990-2000; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Gathering in front of Union Station and Run on the Mall, ca. 1999; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Unlabeled Photographs - Handing out water at a race and a Social Gathering, ca. 1990-2000; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Unlabeled Photographs - At Outback Steakhouse Restaurant, 1990s; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Unlabeled Photograph - Group Picture in Parking Lot, 1990s; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Unlabeled Photographs, 1990s; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Unlabeled Photographs of Various Events - Races, Gatherings, and Candids, 1984-2000; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Unlabeled Photographs - Jingle Bell Run and Dinner Event, 1990s; Series 5 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - 20th Anniversary 2001 Sallie Mae Run, 2001 Spring Fling, Series 5 (Box 12, Cd 1)
  - D.C. Front Runners, Series 5 (Box 12, Cd 2)
  - Fast Forward: D.C. Front Runners 30 Years Running [1 of 2], 2011; Series 5 (Box 12, Dvd 1)
  - Fast Forward: D.C. Front Runners 30 Years Running [2 of 2], 2011; Series 5 (Box 12, Dvd 2)
  - Oversize photographs and posters, 1991-2011; Series 5 (Box 13, Box-folder 1)